<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:atom="https://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification" >
  <title>Milo Land</title>
  <atom:link href="http://www.milofultz.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="http://www.milofultz.com/" />
  <author>
    <name>Milo Fultz</name>
    <email>milopfultz@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <id>http://www.milofultz.com</id>
  <entry>
  <title>gemkill - Generate no-nonsense text-based sites</title>
  <link>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-06-19-gemkill.html</link>
  <guid>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-06-19-gemkill.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;gemkill - Generate no-nonsense text-based sites&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/milofultz/gemkill"&gt;Check out gemkill on Codeberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've been using Jekyll for my website since mid 2020, and it has worked well enough that whole time. The real issue I had that whole time was that I didn't actually understand how Jekyll worked. I just followed a tutorial, did all the steps, clicked stuff, and it worked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was gratifying until I wanted to change *anything*. If there is one thing I know about myself, it's that I really dislike having weird black boxes that I am beholden to. If I don't know how to tweak a thing, or at the very least extricate myself from it if desired, I get really antsy. Merely one more aspect of some long standing emotional baggage, but at least in this instance, it's beneficial!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enter gemkill. You have a folder of pages written in gemtext, an ultra-minimal markup language, and a frame to slam these pages into. Bam. You want an RSS feed, too? Easy, make another frame for that. Done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted it to be pretty no nonsense, and I think I got close. Considering this was a few day project, I feel pretty good about how it turned out! The page you're looking at was built with it, and you can read it, so I'd say it is a success.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Minimalism</title>
  <link>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-06-03-minimalist.html</link>
  <guid>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-06-03-minimalist.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 3 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Minimalism&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minimalism isn't about sterility, it's about intimacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minimalism isn't about having less, it's about having more intentionality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minimalism isn't about design, it's about use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minimalism isn't an aesthetic, it's an action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://simonsarris.substack.com/p/patina-and-intimacy?s=r"&gt;Patina and Intimacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Byonic Reading - 80/20 Version on Bionic Reading</title>
  <link>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-05-21-byonic-reading.html</link>
  <guid>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-05-21-byonic-reading.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Byonic Reading - 80/20 Version on Bionic Reading&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/milofultz/byonic-reading"&gt;Check out the project files on Codeberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://milofultz.codeberg.page/byonic-reading/"&gt;See it in action here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the designer, Bionic Reading is a way to aid in reading comprehension and focus, particularly those with difficulties like dyslexia, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bionic-reading.com/"&gt;Bionic Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bionic Reading revises texts so that the most concise parts of words are highlighted. This guides the eye over the text and the brain remembers previously learned words more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recommend checking it out on their site so you can see what they're getting at. On first glance, the example they used seemed to make sense. It looked like it was merely highlighting the first half of every word as bold. It seems after reading their page it does a lot more than that, but that initial spark got me wondering how easy it would be to implement this as a basic Javascript snippet?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It ended up being fairly straightforward. The pseudocode of the whole thing is:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;MakeByonic(element):
  FOR child of starting element
    CASE element type of
      text node:
        Make first half of text bold
        Replace original text node with newly formatted text
      element node:
        CALL MakeByonic on this child element
    END CASE
  END FOR
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are some weird things you have to do to make all this work with a webpage and some caveats I added to make it a but more readable and pleasant, but overall it's pretty straightforward and was a fun project! I may eventually turn it into a Firefox extension because why not.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;20220610 - Someone else made an extremely thorough version of Bionic Reading here. Can do way more than just bolding the first half of letters.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/axoletl/not-br"&gt;https://github.com/axoletl/not-br&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>My Name In ASCII</title>
  <link>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-05-02-ascii-name.html</link>
  <guid>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-05-02-ascii-name.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 2 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;My Name In ASCII&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I saw some IBM logo in ASCII and wanted to try and recreate it from scratch, so I did and added some shading, too. I'm sure I'll add more artistic ones later, once I get bored.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;█████       █████  ██████  ██████        ██████
██████     ██████  ██████  ██████       ████████
 ██████   ██████    ████    ████       ████  ████
 ███████ ███████    ████    ████       ████  ████
 ███ ███████ ███    ████    ████       ████  ████
 ███  █████  ███    ████    ████   ██  ████  ████
████   ███   ████  ██████  ██████████   ████████
████    █    ████  ██████  ██████████    ██████

█████       █████  ██████  ██████        ██████
██████     ██████  ██████  ██████       ████████
 ▓▓▓▓▓▓   ▓▓▓▓▓▓    ▓▓▓▓    ▓▓▓▓       ▓▓▓▓  ▓▓▓▓
 ▓▓▓▓▓▓▓ ▓▓▓▓▓▓▓    ▓▓▓▓    ▓▓▓▓       ▓▓▓▓  ▓▓▓▓
 ▒▒▒ ▒▒▒▒▒▒▒ ▒▒▒    ▒▒▒▒    ▒▒▒▒       ▒▒▒▒  ▒▒▒▒
 ▒▒▒  ▒▒▒▒▒  ▒▒▒    ▒▒▒▒    ▒▒▒▒   ▒▒  ▒▒▒▒  ▒▒▒▒
░░░░   ░░░   ░░░░  ░░░░░░  ░░░░░░░░░░   ░░░░░░░░
░░░░    ░    ░░░░  ░░░░░░  ░░░░░░░░░░    ░░░░░░

█████       █████  ▓▓▓▓▓▓  ▒▒▒▒▒▒        ░░░░░░
██████     ██████  ▓▓▓▓▓▓  ▒▒▒▒▒▒       ░░░░░░░░
 ██████   ██████    ▓▓▓▓    ▒▒▒▒       ░░░░  ░░░░
 ███████ ███████    ▓▓▓▓    ▒▒▒▒       ░░░░  ░░░░
 ███ ███████ ███    ▓▓▓▓    ▒▒▒▒       ░░░░  ░░░░
 ███  █████  ███    ▓▓▓▓    ▒▒▒▒   ▒▒  ░░░░  ░░░░
████   ███   ████  ▓▓▓▓▓▓  ▒▒▒▒▒▒▒▒▒▒   ░░░░░░░░
████    █    ████  ▓▓▓▓▓▓  ▒▒▒▒▒▒▒▒▒▒    ░░░░░░
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/Abhishek-Ghosh/IBM-ASCII-Logo-For-SSH"&gt;https://github.com/Abhishek-Ghosh/IBM-ASCII-Logo-For-SSH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>My Task Management System</title>
  <link>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-04-17-my-task-management.html</link>
  <guid>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-04-17-my-task-management.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;My Task Management System&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goal of my task management system is mainly to record captured tasks and be reminded that I care about things that aren't shiny objects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;V2&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: It has been a few months, and I have essentially moved all my tasks to a plaintext file and use my `tod_sh` program with a simplified version of this system. It just works and is no nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/milofultz/tod_sh"&gt;`tod_sh`&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So V1 had its issues. Too much maintenance, too many moving parts. I want something simpler that requires essentially zero upkeep, is easy to search, and takes little to no organization. I *really* want to avoid a whole program, since that means I have to maintain that whole infrastructure, and I'd rather be in control of that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, a cool alternative I have found is todo.txt, which seems straightforward. Syntax is essentially parsed left to right with certain prefixes meaning certain things (reminiscent of Carmack's plan files):&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/todotxt/todo.txt"&gt;todo.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tinybrain.fans/the-carmack-plan.html"&gt;Carmack's plan files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prefix/Symbol | Meaning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;`x`: An `x` at the beginning represents complete.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;`(p)`: `p` being a priority marker of some kind, like A-Z or 1-9.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;`YYYY-MM-DD`: Depending on position, date of completion, creation, or date due.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;`+project`: `project` being the project name.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;`@context`: `context` being the context you can perform the task in.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;`key:value`: An arbitrary `key`/`value` pair for your own needs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another quick benefit of this rigid but simple syntax is that getting all your high priority tasks, your tasks from `+project`, or tasks within a certain `@context` is as simple as a &lt;cmd+F&gt;, and deleting/moving all your completed tasks from the file is a basic regex away: `/^x\s.+?$/`.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Examples&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of these are essentially optional, aside from the description, which is comprised of some text and the project, the context, and any other key/value pairs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A more complex example:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;x (A) 20211231 20211212 Cancel media subscriptions +budget @home due:20211231

Complete
x
  Priority
  (A)
      Completion Date
      20211231
               Creation Date
               20211212
                        Description
                        Cancel media subscriptions +budget @home due:20211231
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And a much simpler one:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;x Cancel media subscriptions
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Duh, right? That's the goal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obviously you get more benefit of organization/search with more metadata, but with less, you don't have much to upkeep, so I will probably start with much less and bring in more *only when necessary*. I definitely have a problem with trying to do much all at once and being way too optimistic about what is possible, hence this pursuit and these goals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;My System&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My system within this will be a single `txt` file (since I will be able to open it on Dropbox mobile) that can be searched easily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like I had with V1, I'll have my capture space where things get forwarded in from my email, random stuff I see online, conversations with friends, whatever. Then that will be processed at a regular interval and anything that is actionable can go into there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will notably not be a place for dumping unrefined/unactionable tasks or what Tiago Forte's PARA system calls "Areas" (or continuous areas of commitment). These "Areas" include routines, habits, rituals, jobs, relationships, and essentially anything that is not a simple to define task or project with a defined end goal or end date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;V1&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: This system used to work when I had a more regular schedule and was a freelancer. Now, it has become difficult to maintain something so complicated. I'm looking at other alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This task management system is essentially a stripped down and extensible Getting Things Done system that is application- and tech-agnostic, largely based on this post by Sandra at idiomdrottning.org. I use this with a computer, but this could easily be done without one and some hipster PDAs or just notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://merveilles.town/web/statuses/107121945481166989"&gt;this post by Sandra at idiomdrottning.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hipster_PDA"&gt;hipster PDAs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this system is to externalize as many of my tasks and projects away from my brain into something that I can fully trust. If you don't have to worry about remembering random little things while you do something else, you can work smarter and not harder, as well as do useful analysis on your past, present, and future work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The System&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core system is comprised of these areas:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;the inbox,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the backlog,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the projects,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;the tasks,&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;and the todo.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;These areas can manifest as individual documents (which is what I do), but not necessarily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://danlucraft.com/blog/2008/04/plain-text-organizer/"&gt;not&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.43folders.com/2005/08/17/life-inside-one-big-text-file"&gt;necessarily&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Inbox&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The inbox is where I capture all my ideas and tasks that float around my head, I see online, I get as emails or texts, etc., etc. You really want to put **everything** in there. Assume anything that is not put in the inbox will be forgotten, because most of the time, that's true. Emptying my workspaces (brain, email inbox, text messages, etc.) leads to more focused work and less time worrying about what I "should" be doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This file is just a pile of unorganized stuff that will be processed later. I also use multiple inboxes, to ensure that I can capture wherever I am simply and easily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Backlog&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The backlog is where projects and tasks go that are not relevant right now, but I *do* want to do them sometime. This helps keep the projects document current and relevant while not losing anything important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This file is an unorganized pile of projects and tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Projects&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The projects are where I put anything that can't (or shouldn't) be done all at once. If a task needs to be broken down, it is a project. And that means if it needs to be broken down for you. If you have a hard time with task XYZ and breaking it down helps, do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a task within my project requires multiple steps, I break it down further within the same project. If my project is so big that it feels like I should break it down into more projects and that benefits me, I'll do it but making sure my projects always have extremely actionable tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This file is a list of projects, each with its own list of tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Tasks&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tasks are where I put tasks that are not associated with any projects. These are almost always quick and simple tasks that require nothing to prepare (as that would be more than one step and thus, a project).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also include a list of tasks that I need to do with regularity but are not rigidly scheduled (e.g. get a haircut), organized by what needs to be done next.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This file is a list of recurring and non-recurring tasks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The Todo&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The todo area is where I keep my todo list for the day, as well as templates of recurring tasks. This is what I will reference throughout the day as my stuff I need to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of my todo is a list that I use as a template for tasks I want/need to do every day, like feed my plants, meditate, read, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This file is comprised of a few separated sections with the tasks for the day at the top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Others&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also have a document where I keep things I want to read or listen to later, but I have found that I don't ever really go in there as I don't have a prompt to do so. I think if I were able to maintain *everything* within this system, it would be a win.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Processing The Inbox&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using a modified Eisenhower square, I will go through and be brutally honest about what is in there. Anything in this inbox needs to be placed into one of these categories:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jamesclear.com/eisenhower-box"&gt;Eisenhower square&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Delete: be ruthless! Not everything needs to be done and the 80/20 mindset will benefit you here.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Delegate: this is something that needs to be done but is not my job. This is most applicable in work settings or for people who have assistants.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do it: if the thing in my inbox will take less than five minutes, I'll just do it right then. No point in putting something that simple into your system.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Schedule: if it is something that must be done on a certain date like an appointment, I put it in my calendar. (If you just *want* to do it on a particular date, **don't do this**. Put it in your projects or tasks instead.)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Backlog: it's not important, but it is something I'll want to come back to eventually.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Projects: it's something that requires multiple individual tasks. I'll put it in my projects and flesh it out into multiple discrete tasks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tasks: it's something that doesn't need to be broken down.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pareto_principle"&gt;80/20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I strive to have an empty inbox. An inbox is not a todo list and it shouldn't be.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210411064159/https://www.curaytor.com/blog/Your-Inbox-is-Not-a-To-Do-List"&gt;An inbox is not a todo list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For anything remaining within your system, the process flows like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;       ┌─────── PROJECTS ────────┐
 INBOX ┼─ BACKLOG ─┴──────┐      │
       └─────────────── TASKS────┤
                                TODO
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things go from the inbox into projects or tasks, depending on their complexity, and then from projects or tasks into todo. (And to reiterate, lots of stuff from the inbox should be deleted, never to be seen again. Getting things done is also about having less things to do.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Using The System&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each day, I delete my previous todo list, refill it with my daily template, and peruse my projects and tasks for more tasks to add for the day. When collecting from projects, I mark them as done, and from tasks, I delete them. I mark things in my todo as complete so I can log them at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At a semi-regular interval (at this point, whenever I feel like it, which isn't great), I review my projects, tasks, and backlog to ensure they are up to date and still relevant. This usually means cutting out the cruft and filling in gaps that I missed within projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Meta&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I currently use TXT files with Dropbox, as that is where I keep my stuff synced anyway and you can edit TXT files on your phone in the Dropbox app. I assume you could do this whole system in the Notes app on OSX, as it syncs well, too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the inbox, ensure that you can capture thoughts, todos, and ideas anywhere. That can mean you have a pen and paper system but have a Trello to forward emails to for simplicity and a notes app on your phone for quick jotting when your normal inbox isn't handy. I use a TXT file, a Trello for emails and webpages I find, and my journal for brain dumps that usually happen at the beginning of the day while journaling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://idiomdrottning.org/gtd-basics"&gt;https://idiomdrottning.org/gtd-basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://idiomdrottning.org/supposedly-simpler-than-gtd"&gt;https://idiomdrottning.org/supposedly-simpler-than-gtd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://danlucraft.com/blog/2008/04/plain-text-organizer/"&gt;https://danlucraft.com/blog/2008/04/plain-text-organizer/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.43folders.com/2005/08/17/life-inside-one-big-text-file"&gt;http://www.43folders.com/2005/08/17/life-inside-one-big-text-file&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20210411064159/https://www.curaytor.com/blog/Your-Inbox-is-Not-a-To-Do-List"&gt;http://web.archive.org/web/20210411064159/https://www.curaytor.com/blog/Your-Inbox-is-Not-a-To-Do-List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jamesclear.com/eisenhower-box"&gt;https://jamesclear.com/eisenhower-box&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/todotxt/todo.txt"&gt;https://github.com/todotxt/todo.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://maggieappleton.com/basb"&gt;https://maggieappleton.com/basb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/milofultz/tod_sh"&gt;https://codeberg.org/milofultz/tod_sh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Bonzo Buddy - Delegate your self-care</title>
  <link>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-04-09-bonzo-buddy.html</link>
  <guid>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-04-09-bonzo-buddy.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 9 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Bonzo Buddy - Delegate your self-care&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/milofultz/bonzo-buddy"&gt;Check out the project files on Codeberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have problems with taking care of myself. If given the option to do something that will give me long term benefits versus RIGHT NOW, I will almost 100% take the latter. That is, if *I* am the one who thinks of it. If somebody else mentions it, or I read about it in a book or something, my motivation increases an absurd and not logical amount, leading me to action.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is this ideal? Absolutely not. Is this the way my brain works? Yes, at least it seems so right now. So instead of doing what I usually do in this kind of a situation, which is just to fruitlessly ask "why?" a hundred times until I get frustrated, I found a possible solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A member of the Merveilles posted a link to Taylor.town's nowify and it was intriguing. I've made some projects that try and do this for me forever, expanding on the Pomodoro technique, and tried to implement different prompts throughout my life, with alarms, meditation, etc., but none of them seemed to stick.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://merveilles.town"&gt;Merveilles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://taylor.town/projects/nowify"&gt;Taylor.town's nowify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But this one seemed to make a little more sense for some reason. It's barebones, simple, and self-perpetuating. It just does the thing as long as it is running, asking you if you've done a thing yet *that you yourself asked to be reminded of*. There is nothing revolutionary about this, in fact this is the whole class of task managers, etc. that exist. But those are HUGE and made for much more complex uses. I just need a tap on the shoulder every once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That's all this does. At regular intervals (or until it is finished), you just get a ping and a prompt asking you if it's done, not done, or to skip it. That's it. Over the last week, I have done more to keep myself feeling emotionally regulated and physically healthy than I have in a while, and I feel great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So in summary, if you have daily one-time or recurring tasks that don't have a specific time they need to be done, this could help you. I built this over a weekend with little iterations since then, and I would recommend just building your own, too, since it's easy and lets you add your own little features along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Making A Brainfuck Interpreter</title>
  <link>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-03-12-brainfuck.html</link>
  <guid>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-03-12-brainfuck.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Making A Brainfuck Interpreter&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/milofultz/brainfuck"&gt;Check out my interpreter on Codeberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/milofultz/decrypting-the-original-brainfuck-interpreter/src/branch/main/1%20pbi.c"&gt;The original minified interpreter by Urban Mueller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a while now, I've been digging into C to get a better handle of low-level languages, as well as various esolangs like FRACTRAN. When I found brainfuck, a Turing-complete language consisting of only 8 characters, I knew I had to do *something* with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tinybrain.fans/fractran.html"&gt;FRACTRAN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tinybrain.fans/brainfuck.html"&gt;Brainfuck on my wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've always heard that one of brainfuck's interesting uses for a programmer is that implementing a brainfuck interpreter in a new language is a really good way to learn how that language works. This case was no exception, as my initial run was to build it all from scratch in C, and I really did learn quite a bit. Beyond this, this stoked my desire to look into building compilers, interpreters, and language design in general.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this version was effective and worked, I also learned quite a bit and realized how much simpler I could have made my interpreter by looking at the original one by Urban Mueller (the language's creator). This is a great example of super minified code, and I really enjoyed untying this knot and learning all the subtle intricacies of order of operations with prefix/postfix, comma operators, OR's in place of if statements, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/milofultz/decrypting-the-original-brainfuck-interpreter/src/branch/main/1%20pbi.c"&gt;The original interpreter by Urban Mueller (the language's creator)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/milofultz/decrypting-the-original-brainfuck-interpreter/src/branch/main/3%20pbi%20-%20readable.c"&gt;The expanded version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Deciphering This Minimal Roguelike in C</title>
  <link>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-02-04-deciphering-minimal-roguelike.html</link>
  <guid>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-02-04-deciphering-minimal-roguelike.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 4 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Deciphering This Minimal Roguelike in C&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently found this rad minimal roguelike and wanted to try and figure out what the heck is going on. It's only 512 bytes in C, which is insane, so I had to try and solve this little puzzle I was presented.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.locklessinc.com/articles/512byte_roguelike/"&gt;The rad minimal roguelike&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's not worth going into super detail here, as it's all in the code, and seeing it move from a jumbled code salad into something meaningful is so fascinating to me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.locklessinc.com/articles/512byte_roguelike/"&gt;the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/milofultz/decrypting-the-minimal-roguelike/src/branch/main/3_annotated.c"&gt;my annotated version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>Sub2Pub - Convert Youtube Subtitles to EPUBs</title>
  <link>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-02-01-sub2pub.html</link>
  <guid>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-02-01-sub2pub.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 1 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Sub2Pub - Convert Youtube Subtitles to EPUBs&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/milofultz/sub2pub"&gt;Check out the project files on Codeberg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Converts the subtitles of a Youtube video into an EPUB, using yt-dlp, Calibre, and basic \*nix tools in the shell. This technically works with suto generated subtitles, but it isn't pretty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/yt-dlp/yt-dlp"&gt;yt-dlp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://manual.calibre-ebook.com/generated/en/cli-index.html"&gt;Calibre&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pretty much downloads the raw subtitle file from the YT server, formats everything as an HTML file, and then converst it directly. Works pretty well, and was really fun!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>
<entry>
  <title>My Favorite Web Radio Stations</title>
  <link>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-01-31-web-radio.html</link>
  <guid>http://www.milofultz.com/2022-01-31-web-radio.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;My Favorite Web Radio Stations&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://c7.radioboss.fm:18205/stream"&gt;Bootie Mashup Radio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://trace.dnbradio.com:8000/dnbradio_main.mp3"&gt;DnB Radio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://listen.freeformportland.org:8000/stream"&gt;Freeform Portland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://kwvaradio.uoregon.edu:8000/stream/1/"&gt;KWVA - University of Oregon Campus Radio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://project.stream.laut.fm/project?pl=m3u"&gt;I can't remember the name of this, but I must have saved it for some reason&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://87.117.201.160:8200/listen.pls"&gt;UKG247 - UK Garage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://listen.xray.fm:8000/stream"&gt;XRAY Portland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Silly but cool:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PgbrzmFGUyQ"&gt;Wreckage Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MwtVkPKx3RA&amp;t=0s"&gt;RELENTLESS DOPPELGANGER&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
