<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Milo's Projects and Ramblings</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2020-05-22T23:39:21-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>Milo Fultz</name>
   <email>milopfultz@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>I just found out about Zettelkasten</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/22/zettelkasten"/>
   <updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/22/zettelkasten</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m probably going to do a hack job explaining this, so TL;DR: Zettelkasten makes all of your notes easier to develop, utilize, and organize for whatever you need them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zettelkasten is a way of note taking and cataloguing that was popularized by sociologist Niklas Luhmann. This particular system intrigued me because it seems to overcome the issues that some basic note taking strategies have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note taking, in the way I was taught, is all about writing down what you’re thinking in a stream-of-consiousness, extremely linear way. This can be good for going through a whole thought process and getting it all down, but it’s lacking any ability to be anything but “start here and end up there”. It’s hard to link it to any other ideas without explicitly remembering what your thought process was. It is possible, with use of notes in the margins, post it notes, and maybe a synopsis (which is also a written out linear thought), but is very unwieldy and again relies on your remembering or regularly reviewing your documented info. Kind of defeats the purpose of documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other way is to use a kind of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mind_map&quot;&gt;mind map&lt;/a&gt;. Starting with a basic idea or concept, one branches out into all related things. Maybe “Food” branches off into “Bread”, “Vegetables”, “Nuts”, “Seeds”, and “Fruits”. Maybe “Bread” then branches off into “Focaccia”, “Yeast”, “Sourdough”, “Rolls”, “Pizza”, etc. This can go along for a LONG time, leading people into a more creative exploratory area, kind of allowing their brain to just utilize that free association. The problem that can occur here is again a lack of mobility. Under “Bread”, maybe you want to create some kind of grouping by if it is a yeasted bread, or if it is enriched. Maybe you want to expound on the greatness of sourdough crust on a pizza, where would you put it: under “Pizza” or “Sourdough”? How would you go about organizing these already existing elements in the map without having duplicates or just wasting time moving things around?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that the Zettelkasten can help solve this issue. This allowed Luhmann the luxury of seeing this larger mapping of ideas and freedom of association that the mindmap provides, along with the linearity of thought that the more “academic” linear note taking technique provides, but without their rigid limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my short time playing with this note taking concept, I have used it to take notes on a book I’m reading and help develop some of the major points I’ve seen into things that are relevant to me. I’m able to cross reference from different notes, allowing core concepts to stand on their own and also lead me down expository rabbit holes, allowing a development of smaller ideas that can create new connections once more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, the longer I keep my Zettelkasten, the more robust my index of information, the more connections I can make, the better I can understand and develop my ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because you’re probably wondering what it actually is and not just my real glossy surface level explanation of it, I recommend reading more in depth on it in these two articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/NfdHG6oHBJ8Qxc26s/the-zettelkasten-method-1&quot;&gt;The Zettelkasten Method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://writingcooperative.com/zettelkasten-how-one-german-scholar-was-so-freakishly-productive-997e4e0ca125&quot;&gt;Zettelkasten — How One German Scholar Was So Freakishly Productive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Keyboard Remapping on OSX - Adding the Missing Insert Key</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/22/keyboard-remapping"/>
   <updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/22/keyboard-remapping</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.3eality.com/productions/reality-adlib-tracker&quot;&gt;Reality Adlib Tracker&lt;/a&gt; the other day and realized that Apple removed their insert key abilities a LONG time ago. The insert key is used quite a bit in these older programs for basic things like adding a line in your tracker, creating your pattern sequence, etc. Along with things like Dosbox, where these old relics are utilized, most of these older programs don’t allow new keybindings, so I had to dig around and find a new solution. I unfortunately couldn’t find anything directly related to trackers and stuff on any of their forums, so I figured I’d try and make something that could be found when searching for trackers, DOS, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s one very simple and one not very simple but extremely interesting (read: difficult to understand for a rube like me) solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;simple-and-recommended&quot;&gt;SIMPLE And Recommended:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karabiner-Elements is an open-source program that allows you to remap any key on any device to another key. In this instance, I remapped my right alt/option key to the insert key, as I do not use that option key almost ever. In Karabiner, it’s honestly so simple, as you can see in the screenshot. Choose what key you want to press and what you want it to output. I tested this in RAD and it works beautifully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/20200522karabiner.png&quot;&gt;Check out a picture of my settings here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;not-as-simple-and-honestly-not-recommended&quot;&gt;NOT AS SIMPLE And Honestly Not Recommended:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this way is much more in depth and I honestly don’t really know a lot of what I am doing here. What I tested works for me, but of course YMMV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I utilized the ideas listed in nanoant’s article, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nanoant.com/mac/macos-function-key-remapping-with-hidutil&quot;&gt;“macOS function key remapping with hidutil”&lt;/a&gt;, as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freebsddiary.org/APC/usb_hid_usages.php&quot;&gt;USB HID usage table&lt;/a&gt; and made a couple lines of code that can be input to achieve the same effect as above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/20200522karabiner.png&quot;&gt;Check out a picture of my settings here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go into terminal and type the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hidutil property --set '{&quot;UserKeyMapping&quot;:[
{&quot;HIDKeyboardModifierMappingSrc&quot;:0x7000000e6, &quot;HIDKeyboardModifierMappingDst&quot;:0x700000049}]}'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this does is the hidutil (Human Interface Design utility) is setting a new key map in the following way: key “right alt” is going to now output key “insert”. At this point, it wasn’t working, so I figured I needed to do the opposite, setting the “insert” key to map to “right alt”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hidutil property --set '{&quot;UserKeyMapping&quot;:[
{&quot;HIDKeyboardModifierMappingSrc&quot;:0x700000049, &quot;HIDKeyboardModifierMappingDst&quot;:0x7000000e6}]}'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This made it work for me, and I don’t fully understand, but it is interesting to note. There are a lot of interesting controls in the USB HID image table, so I wonder if I would need any of these strange controls in the future. At least I’ll know how to map them … maybe?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Buying Things &quot;Just In Case&quot; vs. Real Estate</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/22/just-in-case"/>
   <updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/22/just-in-case</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In wondering if I should make a purchase, I noticed a problem with my thinking early on: if something was on sale, I’d buy it, just in case I needed it later to accomplish some goal or in a project I had in mind. The reasoning was that if I bought it now, in a year when I need that very specific thing on that project, then I won’t have to pay what feels like an extra amount, as well as extra time, to go and buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of problems with this line of thinking, mostly that the allure of a sale deluded me into thinking that I will use the thing, making me think about all the things I may need this thing for and justifying it that way. But what finally broke this down for me was thinking about the real estate these things take up and how it affects me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does buying a thing just in case I need it in the future outweigh the costs? Putting extreme situations aside, I pretty much always feel the answer is &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The cost of space. Even with smaller things, there is a cost to house these just-in-case items, especially the more you get. Storage isn’t free, and there is a very real cost to keeping your things organized and maintained.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The cost of finding it when you need it. This problem grows worse and worse the more just-in-case stuff you get. If you have a house full of stuff you might use, you have two choices: spend your time organizing and maintaining that organization, or save that time and then spend that time later trying to find it. Either way, your total time spent goes up with each just-in-case item you buy, and if you feel that your time is worth anything, the time spent in trying to find it later will most likely negate any savings you may have gotten.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The mental cost. With items that are tied to half-done or barely started projects, there is a mental cost to seeing these just-in-case items around the house. When I walked by my oak 1x8’s in the garage, I was reminded that I bought those to build a skateboard and I haven’t done anything with them for two years. For me, being reminded of all of that whenever I walked in the garage gave me a sense of disappointment instead of excitement. If I had scheduled time to finish that project before I bought the supplies, I would have closed the loop, finished the project, and not brought down my mood over those years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The cost of never using it. If you never end up using it, it is a &lt;em&gt;total loss&lt;/em&gt;. I can’t tell you how many times I have bought something just in case, just to try and sell it and then give it to a thrift store 4 years later when I finally gave up the ghost. In these situations, I lost 4 years of space, 4 years of organizing and maintaining it, and the full cost of the item. If I do this with one item out of ten, will that make the other nine worth it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still situations where buying something just in case is actually useful, but I find that is few and far between. At this point, I have much more usable space than I did before, a lot less half-done or barely started projects, and more money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, if I had to choose one side, I would choose real estate over buying things “just in case”.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
